Abraham: There are many different
cyber security controls and there are
many different ways to apply them.
The exact method used will depend
on the type of control and the
system it is being applied to.
Some will be simple processes that
can be executed by the IT department,
but some will involve bringing
in specialists to implement them.
Nicole: So, let’s look at some of
the controls we have already covered.
Passwords, usernames and
multifactor authentication.
To protect against the risk of
phishing attacks more secure
passwords should be used and these
could be changed on a regular basis.
Abraham: The introduction of multifactor
authentication can also reduce
the potential for phishing scams.
If staff leave their passwords lying
around offering easy access to others
having multifactor authentication can
make the system, more secure by having
to add a code sent to a mobile device.
If many employees are working
remotely then remote lock out
can be used if too many incorrect
guesses are made on passwords.
Nicole: Having remote workers can
also have an impact, as remote VPNs
and WiFi connections are notoriously
vulnerable to malware and viruses.
Antimalware can be readily installed
by just hitting an install button
and following instructions.
Encrypting documents and storage
devices can also be done quite easily.
Abraham: Limiting access to
files and folders can be done by
setting up a permissions policy.
By limiting permission there is
less opportunity of inappropriate
access to data and information.
Nicole: The first line of defence
in cyber security is regularly the
employees, as they can often literally
open the door to threat actors.
Implementing periodic security
awareness training for all members of
staff can help to keep the workforce
up to date with the threat landscape.